Welcome back. So, let's complete the
outbox pattern and the next part which
we are covering the CDC, change data
capture. So, polar we have already
covered the polling part.
And now this very important is change
data capture.
So, change data capture is just you can
say that technique and Debezium is the
tool which implement the CDC technique.
So, what does CDC says that? It says
that don't ask the database for changes.
Database will tell you. So, in the
polling
what were happening?
So, we have a DB and we have a table
outbox table.
So, our polar which we have written our
scheduler, right? That was continuously
polling the DB.
Uh this table every 2 second.
And it has because of that it has many
disadvantages.
So, what CDC says that? Don't ask the
database for change. Database will tell
you. So, here now in this our DB we have
outbox table, right?
Whenever there is any insert, update,
delete
so
whatever our process is
this will tell it now that hey
there
is a
change or entry. There is an insert or
update or delete.
Okay? So, now here if you see
we will we don't have to continuously do
the polling.
Now, whenever you will do insert or
update or delete anything into this
particular table
this DB itself will tell you.
So, this technique is called as change
data capture.
Okay? So, how this work? So, understand
this very
uh carefully because in this I'm not
going to tell you the first part. The
first part is let's say your
application.
From that like we have order service,
right? Where we are inserting into the
DB.
Order table.
Outbox table.
So, now I am more focusing on the later
part like once the data inserted into
this table, how how it push
the you can say that updates to a
specific process.
How?
Okay? This one we have already seen,
right? In the polling also the same
thing. Nothing much.
Okay?
But only thing is now we don't write the
polar or we don't write the scheduler.
Scheduler is not required. We don't have
to poll this DB again and again.
Uh once we
insert the data, automatically it should
update to our process that there is an
insert happen or there is an update
happen.
How? Let's see that.
First we need to understand about a
file, let's say WAL, write-ahead logging
file if you are using Postgres.
And uh if you are using MySQL, then you
might have heard of bin log file.
So, what this file is?
In Postgres whenever we do insert,
update, delete
the first
it write into this WAL file only.
And then later it update the table
pages.
It don't directly touch the table pages
first, table first. It first write into
this file, WAL file
and then
later it update the table.
And this help them to like in case of
crash do the recovery. This file is the
source of truth now.
And also in case of replication, let's
say master slave. You have a master DB.
And then you have a slave
DB.
So, master DB
send the updates to the slave DB, right?
So, generally it send this WAL file
only. Similarly in case of MySQL for
replication among the multiple DBs, you
can say that it use bin log file only.
So, CDC
uses
replication logic itself. So, you can
say that
in the DB
the as part of CDC technique your
process
your application process
add itself
as
hey, I you need to replicate the data to
me also. So, you can say that it act as
that
this DB need to send the replication
file to this also.
Okay? So, let's say this is DB slave.
This is DB master.
Okay?
So, whenever there is any change, so
this master DB update the WAL file
to the all the slaves. So, this is the
replication happening.
So, as part of CDC you can say that the
process
add itself
into this replication slot. There is a
slot, replication slot. It add itself as
a
uh replication follower that hey,
whenever any change happen and whenever
you are sending the replication file,
also send it to me. So, now this DB also
send this replication file to this
process also.
Okay?
So, that's the same concept used by CDC,
the replication process.
So, the first thing first, so
uh
you can download Postgres.
This is like uh if you have already done
it
uh
then you can skip this a step.
But if you are doing for the first time,
you can download the Postgres. You can
go to this
Postgresql.org/download.
Based upon your system, Windows, Mac,
Linux, whichever operating system you
are using, download based on that one.
And once you download it, you will also
get PG admin which is like UI for
Postgres. It will automatically comes
with that one.
And once you downloaded it, you can
open. You can server name and give
anything. Host localhost. Port number
5432. The same thing it comes with it.
Database it will automatically create
for us.
Uh user it will automatically
automatically create for us.
Password when you will download it,
right? And when you open it, it will ask
to create a password. The same password
you have to give it here.
And you can connect and open
uh this one.
Now you can write command and all.
Okay? So, if you have already downloaded
the Postgres, well and good. Otherwise,
you can download it like this way.
Now first thing
once you have downloaded your Postgres
or you already have downloaded, you need
to check the WAL level.
Now we are
dealing one level. We are not dealing
with plain SQL queries, right? We are
not interested in insert, update,
delete.
We are more interested in the
replication.
Like our process
our process
should get the file, WAL file properly
so that it can read it.
The fun thing is
WAL level. So, this DB
we know that uh
holds the or maintain the WAL file.
So, this WAL file has currently two
level. One is replica
and another is logical.
We need this WAL level to be logical.
So, earlier it was replica. If it is
replica, we need to change it to
logical.
So, you can run show WAL_level. If it is
replica, you can run this command alter
system set WAL level equals to logical.
Restart the Postgres. It should be
logical. Now you might be asking hey,
why?
By default, see when it's DB to DB
DB and slave when they share the WAL
file
they are you know that if you remember
in the HLD playlist I have shared the
database indexing. In that I have told
how pages are stored.
So, they have everything like okay
page five, offset 120, change from X to
Y.
Our process don't understand that what
is page five, offset 120. It doesn't
understand. It need more information.
Like which table, which column.
Okay? What was the value before? Now
what is the value changed? It need all
those details.
So, that's why it comes with logical.
So, logical
some extra metadata information is also
stored like table, row, column name,
etc. Which is helpful for CDC to publish
the event properly.
Without this in the by default replica,
it has just like pure DB you can say
that uh
terms like page five, offset 120, change
from X to Y.
Which our CDC process you can say that
will not be able to know what exactly
happening.
>> [clears throat]
>> So, that's the first thing we have to
do.
So, in your DB if you have your uh if
you have been using bin log uh
bin file, MySQL or WAL WAL file
you need to change this level, replica
to logical. Very important. Without this
our CDC will not work.
Okay? Uh step two step three is optional
like if you are using JPA
then DB would be created, table would be
created automatically. But I told you
that I am more focusing on
the part two.
Like here. So, currently you can say
that I am not writing this JPA for this
one that table and all. So, I am showing
you the CDC from here.
So, in this one I am also creating the
table. But if you are writing
the Spring Boot application itself, then
this table would be like your entity.
Okay? So, we already have entity, right?
So
this is optional. Either you can
directly create it from this.
Okay, or you can have entity into the
Spring Boot.
So, I've just created a DB outbox CDC
DB.
And in that one, I have created two
table. One is order table, one is outbox
event table. The same thing. Aggregate
type, aggregate ID, event type, payload,
created at. Now, here if you see
published
published true false is not required.
Published at is not required. I told you
that this published is optional and it
is only needed when we are doing
polling.
Now, in case of CDC, as soon as event
come, it pushes.
Okay, it pushes to our process and our
process will consume it.
So, now here if you see,
you have created the DB, you have
created the table.
This is important part.
We have to create the publication. So,
you have to tell the Postgres right that
okay
uh
what data
there could be like 100 tables.
It should not publish
all 100 table to our CDC process.
Okay, so I have created one publication.
Create publication
CDC \underscore} publication for table
and this table I have added.
Okay, outbox \underscore} events. So,
this table, right? Outbox \underscore}
event. In Postgres, everything each
table created under folder public. So,
when you create a publication, you have
to give the complete name space, right?
So, that's why public.
Outbox \underscore} events.
Even if you don't know about public, it
will add it by default.
But this is nothing but a folder. You
can say that that is the structure of
the Postgres. So, here if you see, this
is the Postgres.
All the tables are created inside this
public. And then the tables.
Nothing much.
But understand the meaning of
publication. Publication is that
currently our CDC is not into the
picture.
Okay, just forget about that. Our
Postgres.
Currently, we are just setting up
Postgres. In Postgres, we have 100
table.
But in that one, I have created one
publication CDC publication. Just give
it any name. And in that, I have put
only outbox event table. Only one table.
So, whichever
whichever you can say that process or DB
use this publication.
So, this Postgres will make sure that
only this table, which is there in this
publication
only that updates will go. Unnecessary
why
99 other tables update should go. So,
you can say that this publication is
used for filtering.
So, you can create as many publications
as created. And whichever process want
to use it, they will set this. Like,
hey, I want to use this publication. We
will see that. But currently
at Postgres only, we have just created
one publication CDC publication.
And in that publication, we have said
that okay, only outbox \underscore}
event tables we are interested.
So, now Postgres SQL know that okay, for
order, I need to skip. Outbox event,
yes, I need to stream it if anyone is
subscribing to this publication.
User skip it.
Okay, got it?
Very simple. But at this point of time,
we haven't set up any CDC.
Uh and Postgres has only created this
publication. No one is using it.
So, till now we have done this step.
Okay, so Postgres setup is done. Now, we
are going to move to CDC. But Postgres
setup is done.
Two important thing. After downloading
it change the level.
Okay, from replica to logical
so that in the well
it has some extra information like
table, row, column properly so that our
CDC can read.
DB either uh we are creating through
Spring Boot application or you can
create it through here.
Tables through Spring Boot application
JPA Hibernate or through you can
directly create it here.
This is important. We can create one
publication where unnecessarily we don't
want in the well file, we don't want all
100 files to be sent to our CDC. So, we
have created one publication. Our CDC
will use this publication only.
But currently, we will
currently, nobody is using it. We are
going to set up CDC and that we will use
it.
So, Postgres setup is done.
Now
CDC setup we are doing. So, understand
this diagram.
So, in the Kafka
in the Kafka
till now what we have? We have
controller.
Okay, remember? We have already
controller one, controller two, broker
one, broker two.
In Kafka, there is also Kafka Connect.
This is also present.
Kafka Connect, you can say that
it's a
uh connector.
Okay, you can say that it helps
to connect with the DB.
All it need is plugin.
Also, it act as a publisher.
So
this Kafka Connect
we need to add a plugin Debezium
Postgres plugin. So, we our DB is
Postgres.
So, that's why we are using Debezium
Postgres plugin. If your DB is MySQL,
you need Debezium MySQL plugin. So,
depending upon your DB, you need a
specific plugin.
Okay, and this plugin, you need to
update the Kafka Connect that hey, Kafka
Connect, use this plugin
to connect to the DB.
So
this is very important part which we are
going to now set up.
So, first thing is we need to download
the Debezium Postgres plugin. So, this
is the URL.
And you can download it. So, now first
we are setting up this Debezium Postgres
plugin.
Okay, from this, depending upon your
system, you can
check 3.5.0 latest one. Okay?
Now, very important is you need to
extract. Once you downloaded it, you
need to extract where? Within a Kafka
where you have downloaded the Kafka.
Okay, in that you have to create a
plugins folders. Plugins folder and
inside that, you have to extract it. So,
it will come like this. Debezium
connector
\hyphen} Postgres.
Okay?
So, you downloaded it.
And once you downloaded it, you need to
create a plugins folder and extract
in that one.
Okay, within a Kafka where you have a
Kafka, in that create this plugins
folder. And within that, you have to
extract whatever you have downloaded for
this Debezium.
Now, we have downloaded this Debezium
Postgres plugin.
Now, we have to update the Kafka Connect
that hey, use this plugin.
Okay, so how?
So, in the config within your Kafka,
right? You have this uh bin, config, and
all, right? So, if you go inside config
there is something called Kafka
connect-standalone.properties.
Inside that, you have to add
plugin.path. Currently, it should be
empty.
You need to just update the path
of your this one. Debezium connector
Postgres plugin.
User, Shreyas Jain, downloads. This is
my Kafka. Inside that, plugins. This
one.
So, I have to just update this plugin
path. So, now you can say that our Kafka
Connect now has the information that
which plugin to use for CDC.
So, one thing is done. Our Kafka Connect
has been updated with the plugin.
Okay?
Now
we have to
connect this DB and this Debezium. We
have to connect this arrow part.
So, now here
in the config itself, we have to create
this
Debezium-Postgres-connector.properties.
This property file we have to create.
And within this property file, we have
to
set everything up.
The first thing is name. You can give
any name for this connector.
Class is Debezium our Postgres connector
we are using, right? Debezium Postgres.
If you are using MySQL, Debezium MySQL
connector you would be using it.
Third is like
your localhost, port, username,
password, and the DB name which you are
going to connect.
Okay, so all this information we have to
provide.
This is not necessary, I will tell you,
but you can add it. But this is of no
use.
Table include list.
The table which our CDC is interested in
so I have put here that
public.outbox-events.
This is the table I am interested in
outbox-events. So, you can say that this
is a second level filter.
First level filter was
first level filter.
What was the first level filter, can you
tell? So, if you here see above
at the Postgres setup
Okay. We have a publications, right? We
have set up a publication. Where it
goes?
Publication. So, this publication has
like what all tables we have
added into this publication.
So, you can say that this is this filter
is at
Postgres side.
And this filter would be at
your
CDC side.
Your Kafka Connect side. You can say
that.
Okay, so your table include list is your
currently only interested in outbox
event table.
The slot name is like whatever the slot
name you want to give. Like this slot
name would be created at the post this
side. So post this will create this.
Plug-in name PG output. This is
important like uh
what would happen is
at PG output when you use this plug-in
name valve decode it and then send to
Debezium.
So Debezium now will get to know that
okay, insert into like proper
understandable format by the CDC.
Okay? So valve is in binary format.
Binary format.
Okay? So this plug-in name PG output is
that like it will do decode for us.
And which is understandable by Debezium.
The word CDC.
Okay? A snapshot mode is initial. I will
tell you why it is required. So maybe
let's say already this outbox event
table has 100 records.
And now you are
adding this CDC. Now you are adding this
CDC. So what it does it initial it will
just take read all this 100 record
send an event. And after that as soon as
record come 101, it will get the update
streaming.
Okay?
So snapshot mode is initial means start
with the snapshot of existing data then
stream.
Publication auto create mode disabled.
Why I disabled is because I have already
created one publication at the post this
side. I have created this publication
CDC underscore publication. We want to
use that. So I just gave a publication
name. Publication.name equals to CDC
underscore publication. So you can say
that post this will use it to filter the
table in the valve.
And this is what fun level of filter.
Again here I I have also included
table.include list.
By mistake if let's say in valve more
table data is there still
it is like a second level of filter
here.
Now this is important part like
transforms equals to outbox. You can
give any name like uh
we can give. Now transforms.outbox is
like mapping.
We are doing a mapping.
From the table
like our CDC need to understand, right?
So our CDC need key
payload
topic.
So that thing we are adding.
So transforms.outbox
table field event ID. So event ID is
like unique ID for this event. So use
this column ID.
Table.field.event.key
use this column aggregate ID as the key.
Use this column payload as the
payload.
Okay? And for the topic
route.by.field
aggregate type. So it just read this
column into this field.
Now this is the topic
route.topic.replacement.
This value aggregate type value which
has got here
let's say order
hyphen events. So what you can append
anything after that one. Or if you don't
want to append, don't append it.
So this becomes your topic.
So all we are doing here is that from
the column
of outbox event table we are just
mapping like what should be the key,
what should be the payload, what should
be the topic, what should be the unique
ID.
Okay?
Type is like event router. We are just
routing the event.
Okay? So this is
required for this connection between CDC
and the this one. So when we start this
Kafka Connect process
at that type at that point of time this
Debezium
add itself as a replication follower.
Okay, in this one.
Whatever the DB you have provided
in that it will try to add as a
replication follower. Hey, whatever the
whenever you will send a replication
info send me also but with this rules. I
am only interested publication is CDC
underscore publication.
Okay, if this publication doesn't exist
you might get error.
Okay?
So
with this information it will add.
And now we can start it and check
everything. So here
here if you see controller one is
running you already know how to start
the controller. Controller two is
running broker one is running.
And now here I have just uh started the
Kafka Connect. Okay? So you can use this
command.
You can use this command to run the
Kafka Connect this one.
This Kafka Connect. We have to run this.
Okay?
Now here if you see in this one
I am just giving insert into this table
outbox event table.
order 200.
And insert execute.
So in this table
I have inserted one row.
So now here if you see all this it our
DB should have published the valve file
to our CDC Debezium
which is within this Kafka Connect
process.
And it should have published an event
internally. So I told you right it also
act as a producer.
So it will it would have published an
event. Since we have only one broker.
Okay? So what should be the topic?
As per our logic
I have
aggregate type is order.
Aggregate type is order.
And as per our logic we have
order hyphen
events.
So this is the topic. Okay? And we have
only one broker so it would be oil to
hyphen zero itself. So we can check
that. So the same thing.
So order hyphen events hyphen zero. If
you check it
if you see
order 200. So that's what we have
published 200 201.
Okay?
So if you do 300
and just
you got 300.
So you see I am just adding an entry
into the table
and automatically it publish
to the Kafka. How? Through the technique
of CDC.
And CDC technique is all infrastructure
level. Like no code is required. At
application side the code which is still
required is controller service. You can
say that if table we don't have to
create manually we have this.
Everything same.
You don't need polar itself. That's all.
As soon as you insert into this outbox
repository.saveOutboxEvent
as soon as you do this
the valve file will send to our CDC.
And it will publish an event to the
Kafka.
Got it? So I just show you manually
inserting a query.
Insert query into this table.
I hope it is clear, right? It's all
infrastructure level we have to do.
Nothing much.
Okay? And it's comes with the Kafka
itself. So we don't have to worry about
the scaling and all. So when you have
downloaded the Kafka
uh controller broker this Kafka Connect
comes with it itself.
Okay? All we just need a plug-in. You
can say that the implementation of uh
this CDC.
There might be different implementation
of this tool. Like whichever plug-in you
have to use but Debezium is popular. So
use this
implementation. And you all you just
need to connect.
That's we have to just put. Kafka
Connect two things. Kafka Connect just
need to know which plug-in you are
using.
Okay? Internally automatically it will
talk to that. And all we have to provide
is this linking between DB and the
DB like whichever the plug-in you have
set.
That's all.
I hope it is clear. Any doubt let me
know. We can discuss into the comment
section.
Bye.